#### Contact

melissa.e.acevedo@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ acevedomelissa (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Pediatric Nursing Registered Nurses Nursing Care

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Critical Care Registered Nurse (Pediatric) (CCRN-P) Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards
Academic Dean's List
Highest Honors

# Melissa Acevedo

Pediatric Critical Care Resource Team at UCSF Medical Center Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

## Summary

My goal is to grow professionally as a nurse by utilizing the experience I have gained from my clinical rotations and educational background. My experiences have allowed me to achieve strong clinical skills, develop a good rapport with clients and their families, and accomplish independence by learning how to deliver total patient care to multiple patients with the use of effective time-management and critical thinking skills. I will use my bilingual skills in order to deliver quality patient care to a diverse community.

My clinical rotations are:

Pediatric Referral Unit/Pediatric Transplant Surgical Unit: Holtz Children's Hospital - 200 hours

- Deliver total patient care to five assigned patients while working with increasing levels of independence under the supervision of a Registered Nurse.
- Obtained experience with burn wound care, central lines, intravenous line insertion

Pediatric Cardiac Intensive Care Unit: Miami Children's Hospital - 75 hours

Labor and Delivery: Baptist Hospital of Miami - 75 hours

Community Health: Boys & Girls Club of Miami-Dade - 75 hours

Medical-Surgical: South Miami Hospital - 225 hours

Medical-Surgical: Palmetto General Hospital - 225 hours

Cardiac Telemetry: Aventura Hospital & Medical Center - 150 hours

Long-Term Care Facility: Jackson Memorial Purdue Medical Center - 225 Hours

### Psychiatric Nursing: South Florida State Hospital - 75 Hours

# Experience

UCSF Medical Center
Pediatric Critical Care Resource Team
October 2019 - Present (10 months)
San Francisco Bay Area

Travel RN

Stanford Children's Health | Lucile Packard Children's Hospital Stanford

6 months

CVICU travel RN September 2019 - October 2019 (2 months) Palo alto, CA

Picu travel RN
May 2019 - September 2019 (5 months)
San Francisco Bay Area

Kaiser Permanente PICU Travel RN October 2018 - April 2019 (7 months)

Nicklaus Children's Hospital Intensive Care Nurse January 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 10 months) Miami, Florida

Holtz Children's Hospital
Registered Nurse
April 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 9 months)
Pediatric Transplant Surgical Unit/ Pediatric Referral Unit

Arsi Care Group Caregiver December 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 4 months) Specialize in providing personalized and professional care to children, from infants to adolescents, to meet the needs and preferences of each client. In addition, I help elder clients with impairments with activities of daily living. I provide company and emotional support.

iHealth Corp Insurance Verification Representative May 2011 - June 2012 (1 year 2 months) Aventura, FL

Worked to ensure that patients' health care benefits covered required procedures. Contacted a patient's insurance company to verify coverage levels and worked with individuals to educate them on their benefits information.

Muvico Theaters Supervisor April 2008 - May 2011 (3 years 2 months) Hialeah, FL

My responsibilities were to supervise the work environment and supervise other staff members. Answer customers' questions via phone calls. Obtained customer care knowledge and developed an ability to work in a fast-paced atmosphere while maintaining excellent customer relations. Diplomatically resolved customers complaints on as-needed basis.

## Education

Nova Southeastern University
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2012 - 2014)

Miami Dade College
Associate's Degree, Pre-Nursing Studies · (2009 - 2011)

Hialeah High School (2005 - 2009)